Mohammad Ilyas Kohistani

Full-Stack Web Developer

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

I was a Full Stack and Mobile Application Developer at IGW (Info Gateway) Afghanistan, Full Stack Developer and promoted to Project Manager at Remotify Turkey, Full Stack Developer at Limonist, Developers Team Lead at Wam Denim. I have over 5 years of professional work experience in project management, Web Application Development, Mobile Application Development, UI/UX Designing, Database Designing, API Development, Dynamics 365 Extension Development and Testing, Integration and Implementation at different local and International Organizations, such as Wam Denim International, Limonist International, IGW Afghanistan and Remotify Turkey. As a result, I have got extensive experience in working with Laravel Framework, Vue.js Framework, Node.js, Socket.io, Flutter, Dynamics 365 Extension Development, SQL Server, MySQL, API Development, Trello Application and Handling all steps of the development lifecycle; from requirements gathering/estimating to customer support and enhancements.

I have received my Bachelor's degree in Computer Science with a specialization in Software Engineering from Kabul University (KU) of Afghanistan. Moreover, I have received Leadership Development Certificate and Afghanistan Youth to Business Forum 2019 Committee Member Certificate. In addition, I have received training in Event Management, Youth for Global Goals, From Ideas To Business and 17 SDGs (Sustainable Development Goals) Learning.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Developers Team Lead WAM DENIM ∅	01/2022 – 05/2022 Istanbul, Turkey
Full-Stack Developer Limonist &	07/2021 – 12/2021 Istanbul, Turkey
Full-Stack Developer/Project Manager Remotify &	07/2020 – 06/2021 Ankara, Turkye
Full-stack web developer IGW Organization (Remotely)	2016 – 2022 Kabul, Afghanistan
Mobile Application Developer IGW Organization (Remotely)	2020 – 2021 Kabul, Afghanistan

DDOILGE DACE EXPEDIENCE	
PROJECT BASE EXPERIENCE Softinya For-profit learning platform in Turkey.	2021
Remotify \mathscr{D} Find and manage a freelance workforce with embedded best practices and high standards.	2020 – 2021
Lotus & Lotus cafe house management system	2020
SDROA ERP MIS Mobile application for SDROA organization.	2020
EventHub An easy event management mobile application.	2019
SDROA MIS (Management Information System) <i>⊗</i> MIS system for SDROA organization.	2018

INTERNSHIP

ALPHA Afghanistan

2018 – 2020

Event manager

Kabul, Afghanistan

AIESEC ⊘

Responsible for Outgoing Exchange/Event Manager

AIESEC in India 🔗

Leadership development experience through a global volunteer opportunity tackling the sustainable development goal decent work and economic growth.

Certificate ID: 4830018

Kabul, Afghanistan

12/2018 - 02/2019 Delhi, India

2018 - 2020

EDUCATION

Bachelor degree/computer science 2016 - 2019 Kabul University

Degree of high school 2015 Ghulam Haidar Khan

COURSES	
The Complete Node.js Developer Course (3rd Edition) Udemy	2020
React & Redux Udemy	2019
Vue JS Essentials with Vuex Udemy	2019
Advanced CSS and Sass: Flexbox, Grid, Animations and More! Udemy	2018
PHP with Laravel	2016

SKILLS

Udemy

• PHP	• Laravel	 Laravel Telescope 	 Laravel Passport
 Codeigniter 	• Dynamics 365	• C/AL	• Node.js
• Vue.js	• Trello	 JavaScript 	• jQuery
• MySQL	• SQL Server	• Socket.io	• JWT
• API Development	• Postman API	 Hosting 	• React
• Redux	• HTML5	• Ajax	 CSS, Grid, Flexbox
• SASS	• Flutter	• ASP.NET	 Android Studio

LANGUAGES

• Persian • English • Turkish • Pashto